Preliminary Inventory to the United States. Dept. of State Records
Hoover Institution Archives
United States. Dept. of State Records,
1942-1990
44006
Hoover Institution Archives
6 manuscript boxes (2.3 linear feet)
Mimeographed reports, 1942-1943, relating to the imposition of international sanctions against aggressor nations, and to the effects of League of Nations sanctions against Italy in 1935 1936; microfiche copies of reports, memoranda, and correspondence, 1967, relating to the Israelinaval and air attack on the U.S.S. Liberty on 8 June 1967, issued byvarious offices of the Department of State, and publicly released under the Freedom of Information Act; and photocopies of Department of State correspondence, dispatches, reports, and memoranda, 1957-1990, released under the Freedom of Information Act, relating to political and economic conditions in Hong Kong, riots in Hong Kong in 1966 and 1967, Vietnamese refugees in Hong Kong, and the prospective transfer of Hong Kong to China in 1997
United States. Dept. of State.
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in increments since 1944.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content Note
This collection mainly contains photocopies of Department of State correspondence, telegrams, dispatches, and reports, requested and released under the Freedom of Information Act. These documents relate to the political and economic conditions in Hong Kong, riots in Hong Kong, Vietnamese boat people in Hong Kong, and the prospective transfer of Hong Kong from British rule to China.
League of Nations--Sanctions.; Liberty (Ship); United States. Navy.; Aggression (International law); China--Foreign relations--United States.; China.; Hong Kong (China); Israel--Foreign relations--United States.; Israel-Arab War, 1967--Naval operations.; Israel.; Italo-Ethiopian War, 1935-1936.; Sanctions (International law); United States--Armed Forces--Mediterranean Sea.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations--Israel.; United States--Foreign relations.; Vietnamese--China--Hong Kong.
- Mimeographed reports, relating to the imposition of international sanctions against aggressor nations, and to the effects of League of Nations sanctions against Italy in, 1942-1943, 1935-1936 (Box 1: 1)
- Microfiche copies of reports, memoranda, and correspondence, relating to the Israeli naval and air attack on the U.S.S. Liberty on issued by various offices of the Department of State, and publicly released under the Freedom of Information Act, 1967, 8 June 1967 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Photocopies of Department of State correspondence, dispatches, reports, and memoranda, released under the Freedom of Information Act, relating to political and economic conditions in Hong Kong, riots in Hong Kong in Vietnamese refugees in Hong Kong, and the prospective transfer of Hong Kong to China in, 1957-1990, 1966 and 1967, 1997 (Box 2-5)
- Freedom of Information Act Requests Inventory, undated (Box-folder 1: 3)
- "Documents on Aggression or Definition of Aggression," report, 1942 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- Correspondence
  - Transfer of Sovereignty over Hong Kong from Britain to China, 1982 (Box-folder 1: 5-11)
  - Regarding Discussions between U.S. and Hong Kong Officials, 1983 (Box-folder 1: 12, 2: 1-2)
  - The Brain Drain, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Discussions between the U.S. Consulate and Officials of the Xinhua Agency in Hong Kong, 1979, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - The Effects of Hong Kong's Transfer to Mainland Rule on Hong Kong's Economy, 1986, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Elections to the Legislative Council, 1985, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Elections to the District Boards, 1982, 1985, 1988 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - The Development of Representative Government in Hong Kong, 1983 (Box-folder 2: 8-11)
  - U.S. Warships in Hong Kong During the 1967 Disturbances, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - U.S. Policy toward Hong Kong, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Discussions Relating to Hong Kong between Mrs. Thatcher and George Bush in Bermuda, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Discussions between SecState Baker and ForSec Hurd relating to Hong Kong, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Discussions on Hong Kong between Zhao Ziyang and U.S. Officials, 1984 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Discussions between Deputy Sec State Stossel and Hong Kong Governor Maclehose, 1981 (Box-folder 2: 17)
  - Discussions relating to Hong Kong between National Security Advisor Zbigniew Brezezinski and Chinese Officials, 1978 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Hong Kong's Basic Law, 1990 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - The Effects of the June 4 Massacre on Hong Kong, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Vietnamese Boat People in Hong Kong, 1989 (Box-folder 2: 21, 3: 1-3)
  - Xinhua Director Xu Jiatun, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - The Future of the U.S. Consulate in Hong Kong, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - The Joint Declaration, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Martin Lee, 1988 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - The HKG's Green Paper on Democracy, 1987 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Mrs. Thatcher's Trip to Beijing, 1982 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Hong Kong Governor David Wilson's Trips to Beijing, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Joint Liaison Group's Meetings, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Ji Pengfei's Visit to Hong Kong, 1985 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Lu Ping's Visit to Hong Kong, 1986 (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Youde's Visit to China, 1986 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Governor Wilson's Trips to London, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 15)
  - Governor Youde's Trips to Beijing, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 3: 16)
  - Governor Youde's Trips to London, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 3: 17)
  - Hurd's Visit to Hong Kong, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Geoffrey Howe's Visits to Beijing, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Geoffrey Howe's Visits to Hong Kong, 1990 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Peroy Cradock's Visit to Beijing, 1989 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Riots in Hong Kong, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 1-4)
  - Reform of the Hong Kong Government in Hong Kong, 1966, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - HKG's Green Paper on Representative Government, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - Influx of Vietnamese Refugees from China, 1987 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - From Lloyd, Selwyn to Dulles, John, 1957 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Meeting with Dwight D. Eisenhower and Harold McMillan, 1957 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - British Minister Francis Maude's Trip to the U.S., 1990 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Meetings of the Sino-British Joint Liaison Group, 1985, 1988 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - From American Consulate Hong Kong to Secretary of State Washington, 1990 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Zhou Enlai's Meeting with Lord Montgomery, 1961 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Hong Kong's Status, 1968-1982 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - U.S. Government's Policy towards Hong Kong, 1970-1971, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Economy of Hong Kong, 1981-1982, 1984, 1991 (Box-folder 5: 8)
- Printed Matter
  - Hong Kong Disturbances, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 9)